Linxuan Chen

Markham, Ontario • 514-663-8404 • linxuanchen2017@gmail.com github.com/Linxuan-Chen/ • linkedin.com/in/chen-linxuan-120053187/ https://linxuan-chen.github.io/My_React_Website/#/

QUALIFICATIONS PROFILE

Master's degree of Electrical and Computer Engineering program from Concordia University with over 2 years hands-on experience in front end development. Worked in **world top 500 company Alibaba**. Adept at developing reusable UI components utilizing a variety of tools and environments.

Core Technologies

Front-end Skills: ReactJS, VueJS, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, Ant Design (CSS framework),

Javascript (ES6), jQuery (Ajax), Axios, Jest, Git, SEO, Responsive Web Design, Single

Page Application, Agile development, Photoshop.

Back-end Skills: Node.js, JSON
Database: MySQL, MATLAB

Language: English, French, Mandarin

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Master of Electrical and Computer Engineering – 5/2020 Concordia University, Montreal, Quebec

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering and Automation – 5/2016 Nanjing University of Science and Technology, Nanjing, China

EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

Alibaba Group, Nanjing, Jiangsu Province, China

Alibaba is the world's largest retailer and e-commerce company, and on the list of largest Internet companies. Its three main sites Taobao, Tmall and Alibaba.com have hundreds of millions of users, and host millions of merchants and businesses. Its online sales and profits have surpassed all US retailers (including Walmart, Amazon, and eBay) combined since 2015.

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT INTERN, 05/2019 – 6/2020

Technologies: Agile, ES6, React, React-Router, Redux, Ant Design, Ajax, HTML5, CSS3, Ant-design Projects:

1. Improving UI/UX of Taobao BI analyser tool

Brief Introduction: A website product aimed at merchants on Taobao ecommerce platform providing a visualized method to reach Alibaba's existed cloud and data analysis products. It's a joint between merchants and elusive BI reports.

Job Description:

Linxuan Chen

Page Two

- Agile Development.
- Built reusable UI components using ReactJS and Ant-Design that display data and views of backstage management system.
- Used One-Design internal library to display data results visually.
- Fetched data from server side via Restful APIs utilizing ES6 fetch.
- Set routers using React-Router.
- Managed data and React states by Redux and React-Redux.
- Provided general application maintenance.

2. Completed UI of ONENESS Platform

Brief Introduction: An internal platform provides connection to most Alibaba's data product interfaces to assists developers in fetching results from Alibaba's data products or Cloud services.

Job Description:

- Constructed UI components and routers.
- Fetched and managed data by restful APIs using Axios.

ThoughtWorks Software Technology Co., Shanghai, China

ThoughtWorks is a global technology company who provides software design and delivery, and tools and consulting services.

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT INTERN, 2/2016 – 3/2017

Technologies: ES6, React, React-Router, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Ajax

Provided front end development for Community Residents Management System utilizing React.

Brief Introduction: A product based on website to offer property management companies an easier way to administrate the community. It offers portals for residents to upload personal information and to provide feedbacks as well as visualized backstage interfaces for administrators to read feedbacks and to post notifications.

Job Description:

- Built routers and reusable UI components using React and React-Router.
- Used Ajax to fetch data from server side.
- Used Redux to store states.
- Adapted to company toolset, quickly and efficiently learning all unique frameworks and concepts.

Concordia University, Montreal, Quebec

MASTER'S STUDENT, ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING, 5/2017 – 5/2020

Acquire and apply knowledge of current and emerging high-level software development practices, including system control (optimization techniques, large system control, real time system control,

Linxuan Chen

Page Three

robotics), signal processing (digital signal processing, medical image processing, digital video processing), and microprocessing.

- Prototyped smart parking system using ARM microprocessor which is a real model composed with ARM microprocessor, RFID system, laser sensors, LED screens and motors. It uses RFID system to inquiry users' account, microprocessor to find the best slot, to check the account status and to control LED screen and motors.
- Experience with building responsive website with frameworks like bootstrap or with CSS media query to enhance mobile user's experience.
- Completed some open source projects on my own on GitHub. All of them are responsive and are friendly to mobile users.
 - Rebuilt the homepage of Eduwork institution using React, React-Router, Redux, Bootstrap,
 Sass and DPlayer.

Demo: https://linxuan-chen.github.io/EduWork/

 Constructed my personal website using React, React-Router, Bootstrap, React-Bootstrap, Module CSS, Sass and Swiper.js.

Demo: https://linxuan-chen.github.io/My React Website/#/

Completed a demo of to do list using React, React-Router, Redux and Sass.

Demo: https://linxuan-chen.github.io/To-Do-List/

- Built filter for denoising ultrasound images by MATLAB.
- Developed a system for tracking specific targets in videos using MATLAB.